Finding Aid for Lana Pollack Papers 1979-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Campaigns
  - United States Congress, 1988
    - Jewish and Israeli Interests, 1987-1989 (Box 11)
    - Lenawee County, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Livonia, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Low Level Radioactive Waste, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Media Consultants (Axelrod and Associates), 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Nominating Petition, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Office Memos, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Opponent File, Carl Purcell, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Opponent File, Dean Baker, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Out of District, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Phone Bank, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Photo Contacts, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Plymouth, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Political Action Committees (PACS)
      - Arms Control, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Communications, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Construction Building Trades, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Education, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Environment, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Federal Employees, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Financial Lists, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Firemen, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Food, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Foreign Policy, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Handicapped, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Israel, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Lawyers and Social Workers, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Marine, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Mass Transit, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Medicine, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Neighbor to Neighbor, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Performing Arts, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Political, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Seniors, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Teachers, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Textiles, 1988 (Box 11)
      - United Auto Workers (UAW), 1988 (Box 11)
      - Unions, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Women's Action for Nuclear Disarmament (WAND), 1988 (Box 11)
      - Women, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Polling, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Pre Campaign, 1985-1987 (Box 11)
    - Precinct Targeting, 5/13/1988 (Box 11)
    - Press Releases, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Questionnaires, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Schedules, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Senior Citizen Prescription Drug Bill, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Staff Meetings, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Statements, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Students for Pollack, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Television and Radio, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
    - Volunteers, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Voter Files, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Voting Record, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Washtenaw County, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Wayne County, 1988 (Box 12)
  - United States Senate Democratic Primary, 1994
    - Opponent Files
      - Abraham, Spencer, 1994 (Box 12)
      - Blanchard, James, 1994 (Box 12)
      - Brodhead, William, 1994 (Box 12)
      - Camp, Dave, 1993 (Box 12)
      - Carr, Robert, 1976-1994
        - Anti-Carr Campaign Releases, 1994 (Box 12)
        - General, 3 folders (Box 12)
        - Dingell Contribution, 1994 (Box 12)
        - Education, 1983-1993 (Box 12)
        - Issue files, 1994 (Box 12)
        - Political Overview, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Position Papers, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Savings and Loan, 1987-1990 (Box 13)
        - Seniors, 1981-1994 (Box 13)
        - Stocks, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Voting Record, 1982-1994 (Box 13)
      - Coon, Jon, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - DiNello, Gilbert, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Elsman, Jim, 1993 (Box 13)
      - Ferguson, Joel, 1994 (Box 13)
      - FOIA [Freedom of Information Act] forms, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Kelly, John, 1994 (Box 13)
      - McNamara, Edward, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Marlinga, Carl, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Military Records, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Miller, Judith, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Pursell, Carl, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Riegle, Donald, 1993 (Box 13)
      - Romney, Ronna, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Secchia, Peter, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Fundraising
      - Campaign Contributions, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Celebrities, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Contacts
        - AIPAC, 1993 (Box 13)
        - Ann Arbor, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Big Donors (Box 13)
        - Boston, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Business Leaders List, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - California, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Detroit, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Emily's List, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Flint (Box 13)
        - General, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Grand Rapids, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Labor, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Lansing, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Memo from Campaign Staff, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Michigan Women's Foundation, 1993 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 13)
        - NYC, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Saginaw, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Southeast Michigan, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Southeast Michigan, Big Donors, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Veterans, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Washington, DC, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Contributor Profile, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Direct Mail Letters, 1994 (Box 13)
      - Invitations, 1991-1994 (Box 13)
      - Lists and Correspondence, 1990-1994; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Outreach
        - General (Box 13)
        - American Israel Chamber of Commerce Reception, 1993 (Box 13)
        - Jackson, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Labor, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
        - Oakland County, 1994 (Box 13)
        - New York, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - UAW, 1993 (Box 13)
        - Women, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Planning
        - Background, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Calendars, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Schoenberger, Marlene, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
      - Special Events
        - AFL-CIO, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
        - Artists, 1994 (Box 13)
        - Axelrod & Associates, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
        - Dearborn, 1993 (Box 13)
        - Democratic Senatorial C.C., 1994 (Box 13)
        - Emily's List, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
        - Fleischman Party, 1993 (Box 14)
        - Flint, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Golf, 1994; 2 folders (Box 14)
        - Grand Rapids, 1991 (Box 14)
        - Greden, John & Renee, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Huron Valley Labor Council, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Kalamazoo, 1991-1993 (Box 14)
        - Kidd Gallery, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Labor, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Louis Café, 1994 (Box 14)
        - NOW, 1994 (Box 14)
        - National Women's Political Caucus, 1994 (Box 14)
        - New York, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Oakland County, 1991-1993 (Box 14)
        - New York Event
          - Invitations and Schedule, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
          - Lists, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
        - Palmer Woods, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Portnoy, Lynn, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Prospecting, 1993 (Box 14)
        - Bonnie Raitt, 1992-1994 (Box 14)
        - Scherer, Karla Foundation, 1993 (Box 14)
        - Teamsters, Joint Council #43, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Tobias, Emily, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Washington DC, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Women's Campaign Fund, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Wozniak Fundraiser, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Telephone Project, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Organization and Strategy Files
      - AFL [American Federation of Labor], 1994 (Box 14)
      - APA [American Psychiatric Association], 1994 (Box 14)
      - Banks, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Boilermakers, 1993 (Box 14)
      - Business Paper, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Campaign
        - Handouts, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Nice Letters, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Plan by Campaign Design Group, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Strategy Memos, 1994 (Box 14)
        - Update, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Carpenters and Joiners, 1994 (Box 14)
      - City PAC, 1993 (Box 14)
      - Communications Workers of America, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Congressional Quarterly, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Council for a Livable World, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Endorsements, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Federal Election Commission, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Ford, Congressman Bill, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Gun Nuts/ Threats, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Hollywood Women's Political Committee, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Jewish Strategy, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Labor, 1994 (Box 14)
      - League of Conservation Voters, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Lightning Bolt Newsletter, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
      - Michigan Democratic Party, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Personnel, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Pollack, John, 1993 (Box 14)
      - Polls by Mellman, Lazarus, Lake, 1993-1994; 3 volumes; 1 folders (Box 14)
      - Post-Primary, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Questionnaire Responses, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Scheduling, 1993-1994; 10 folders (Box 15)
      - Smith, Alma Wheeler, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Staff Meetings and Goals, 1994 (Box 15)
      - United Auto Workers, 1994 (Box 15)
      - Volunteer Profiles, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Press Releases and Clippings
      - Chronological, 1994; 7 folders (Box 15)
      - Topical
        - Abortion, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Ann Arbor Politics, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Background on LP, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Business, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Campaign to Promote Responsibility, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Constituent Service, 1992-1994 (Box 15)
        - Crime, 1992-1994 (Box 15)
        - Debate, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Discrimination, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Environment, 1990-1994 (Box 15)
        - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Gay and Lesbian Issues, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Golf Course, 1992 (Box 15)
        - Guns, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Health Care, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Higher Education, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Israel, 1989-1994 (Box 15)
        - Jewish News, 1993-1994 (Box 15)
        - Labor, 1993-1994 (Box 15)
        - Lawyers, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Ludington Coverage, 1993 (Box 15)
        - McDiarmid, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous, 1993-1995 (Box 15)
        - NAFTA [North American Free Trade Agreement], 1994 (Box 15)
        - Perks, 1993-1994 (Box 15)
        - Pledge, 1988-1994 (Box 15)
        - Sex Offenders, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Taxes, 1994 (Box 15)
        - Weeks, George, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Pollack, Lana Research Files
      - Biography and Position Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 16)
      - Research Report (includes biography, issues related background, Senate voting history, OEF Reports, Interest Group ratings, and Senate Select Committee on Education), 1994; 6 volumes (Box 16)
  - Save Our Lands, Save Our Future Campaign
    - Budget, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Clippings, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Contracts and Leases, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Direct Mail
      - Direct Mail Plan and Contract, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Direct Mail Program and Message, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Endorsements, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Fundraising, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Land Use Studies (Michigan Environmental Council), 1998 (Box 17)
    - Opposition and Debates, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Other Land Preservation Programs, 1997-1998 (Box 17)
    - Polling, 1997-1998 (Box 17)
    - Post Election
      - Afterthoughts (includes correspondence and press clippings), 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Polling, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Washtenaw County for Respectable Growth Fundraising Report, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Steering Committee
      - Agendas, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Volunteer Program, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Washtenaw County Board of Commissioners
      - Agricultural Lands and Open Space Plan, 1997 (Box 17)
      - Agricultural Lands Working Session, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Purchase Development Rights Ordinance, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Washtenaw County Election Results, 1994-1998 (Box 17)
- Photographs
  Photographs of Pollack with Governor James Blanchard, Geraldine Ferraro, Bo Schembechler and others.
  - 1983
    - LP with Candidate Powell (Box 17)
  - 1986
    - "Our Choice" Fundraiser in Ann Arbor (Box 17)
  - 1988
    - LP with UAW representatives (Box 17)
  - 1989
    - LP with Governor Blanchard and staff at the signing of the anti-corporal punishment bill (Box 17)
  - 1990
    - LP with Governor Blanchard and Bo Schembechler (Box 17)
  - 1991
    - Geraldine Ferraro reception (Box 17)
  - 1992
    - LP with Elsa Cole, Edie Goldenberg and Mary Anne Swain at a University of Michigan Rose Bowl reception (Box 17)
- Audiotapes
  Recordings of interviews, speeches, campaign-related radio advertisements and debates.
  - Reel to Reel
    - "No Tax" Radio Spot, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Cassettes
    - undated
      - Northville Record Debate (Box 17)
      - Washtenaw Community College Speech (Box 17)
      - Women's Economic Issues Speech (Box 17)
    - 1983
      - Off the Record, with Senator Lana Pollack, November 4, 1983 (Box 17)
    - 1984
      - AAUW Women's Work Shop Key Note Speech, February 23, 1984 (Box 17)
    - 1988
      - Debate (Box 17)
      - Jackson Underwriters (4/21/88) and Jackson State Retirees (5/2/88) Speeches (Box 17)
      - Pollack and Dean Baker Forum at WAND Meeting (Box 17)
      - Radio Spots (Box 17)
    - 1989
      - Press Conference, April 24, 1989 (Box 17)
    - 1992
      - Reproductive Freedom (Box 17)
    - 1994
      - Legislative Service Bureau, November 22, 1994 (Box 17)
      - Soapbox Summer on WEMU, June 23, 1994 (Box 17)
    - 2006
      - Benton Harbor City Commission meeting excerpt, October 9, 2006 (Box 17)
- Videotapes, VHS
  Videotapes of campaign-related television advertisements, events, debates and interviews.
  - 1985
    - Debate on Part-Time Legislature, July 16, 1985 (Box 17)
  - 1988
    - Pollack for U.S. Congress, television spots (Box 17)
    - Various television spots (Box 17)
  - 1994
    - Interview (Box 17)
    - "Capitol Report" interview, January 21, 1994 (Box 17)
    - Gallup Park Fun Run, Senate Campaign, July 24, 1994 (Box 17)
    - Lana Pollack for U.S. Senate, television spots, July 16, 1994 (Box 17)
    - "Let's Talk" interview, March 4, 1994 (Box 17)
- Other Projects
  The Other Projects series documents Pollack’s activities after leaving the Michigan Senate, including her tenure on the board of the Michigan Natural Resources Trust Fund and her involvement with Jean Klock Park in Benton Harbor, MI. These documents include working files, press releases, minutes, and grant applications.
  - Jean Klock Park, Benton Harbor, Mich.
    - Agency Documents
      - DEQ, 2006-2007 (Box 18)
      - DNR, 2006 (Box 18)
      - Historic Preservation, 2007 (Box 18)
      - Jim Woods Reports, 2009 (Box 18)
      - Southwestern Michigan Planning Commission, 2006 (Box 18)
      - US Park Service, 2006-2007 (Box 18)
    - Background
      - Plan, 1998 (Box 18)
      - Dedication Info, 1917 (Box 18)
      - Development Agreement, 2005 (Box 18)
      - Government Task Force (Box 18)
    - Benton Harbor Proposal (Box 18)
    - City Resolution and Lease Agreement, 2006 (Box 18)
    - Conversion Proposal
      - Conversion and Mitigation Proposal, 2008 (Box 18)
      - Appendix I, 2006; 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Appendix III, 2006 (Box 18)
    - Draft Mitigation Plan, 2010 (Box 18)
    - Harbor Shores Ads, Publications, and Statements, 2006-2009 (Box 18)
    - Harbor Shores Study and Plans, 2005-2007 (Box 18)
    - Lawsuit and Court Documents, 2006 (Box 18)
    - Lease and Management Agreement, 2008 (Box 18)
    - Maps (Box 18)
    - Memos and Meetings, 2006-2009 (Box 18)
    - Mitigation Parcel Info, 2009 (Box 18)
    - Mitigation Strategy, 2010 (Box 18)
    - MNRTF Minutes, 2004-2010 (Box 18)
    - Opposition Research -- Nicole Moon Materials, 2007-2010 (Box 18)
    - Pictures (Box 18)
    - Press, 2008 (Box 18)
    - Public Comments (Mostly Opposition), 2006-2009 (Box 19)
    - Public Comments Summary and Response (Box 19)
  - Michigan Natural Resources Trust Fund
    - Active Issues, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Board Meeting, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Detroit Riverfront Conservancy, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Finances, 2009 (Box 19)
    - Grant Applications
      - General, 2010 (Box 19)
      - Acquisition, 2010 (Box 19)
      - Development, 2010; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Jean Klock Park, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Parting Thoughts, 2010 (Box 19)
    - Rules, Procedures, and Guidelines, 2006-2008 (Box 19)
    - Saugatuck, 2009-2010 (Box 19)
    - State Parks, 2010 (Box 19)